Every bloodline has a beginning.
Dracula Untold is a horror, action, fantasy film directed by Gary Shore.
Vlad Tepes is a great hero, but when he learns the Sultan is preparing for battle and needs
to form an army of 1,000 boys, he vows to find a way to protect his family.
Vlad turns to dark forces in order to get the power to destroy his enemies and agrees to go
from hero to monster as he's turned into the mythological vampire, Dracula.
Vlad Tepes / Dracula, played by Luke Evans.
Mirena / Mina Murray, played by Sarah Gadon.
Mehmed II, played by Dominic Cooper.
Ingeras, played by Art Parkinson.
Master Vampire, played by Charles Dance.
Dimitru, played by Diarmaid Murtagh.
Dracula Untold is a 2014 American action horror film directed by Gary Shore in his
feature film debut, and written by Matt Sazama and Burk Sharpless.
Based on an original screenplay by Sazama and Sharpless, the plot creates an origin story for
the title character, rather than using the storyline of Bram Stoker's Dracula.
In this adaptation, Dracula is the historical figure Vlad III "the Impaler" Dracula and transforms into
his monstrous alter ego to protect his family and kingdom from Ottoman Sultan Mehmed II.
Luke Evans portrays the title character, with Sarah Gadon, Dominic Cooper,
Art Parkinson and Charles Dance cast in supporting roles.
Principal photography began in Northern Ireland on August 5, 2013.
Universal Pictures released the film in regular and
IMAX cinemas on October 10, 2014.
Dracula Untold grossed $217 million worldwide and
received mixed reviews from critics.
The film explores themes of hero, monster, vampire, bite, bravery.
The tone is dark and intense.